现在播送《二零二三年武汉市初中毕业生学业考试
英语试卷听力部分》。
该部分分为第一、第二和。第三节。
注意，做题时先将答案画在试卷上。
该部分录音内容结束后，你将有两分钟的时间将你的答案转涂到英语答题
卡上。
第一节。
听下面四个问题，每个问题后有三个答语。
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每个问题后，你都有五秒钟的时间来作答和。阅读下一小题，
每个问题仅读一遍。
Text 2 How long have you been in Wuhan?
Text 3 Where did you get the news?
Text 4 What's your teacher like?
第一节到此结束。
第二节，听下面八段对话，
每段对话后有一个小题，
从题中所给的。
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听完每段对话后，你都有十秒钟的时间来作答有关小题和阅读下一小题。
每段对话仅读一遍。
Text 5 It's going to be sunny tomorrow.
No clouds, no rain.
good news. Let's have a picnic.
Text 6 How did you get to school today, In my dad's car.
But I usually ride my bike or take the bus.
Text 7 Excuse me, do you have any chicken sandwiches?
Sorry, sir. We only have beef and egg sandwiches.
Text 8 Have you ever been to Xi 'an?
Yes, I've been there three times.
Once for business, twice for traveling.
I've been three for traveling.
Text 9 Class, do you know how to avoid causing a fire at home?
I've got an idea, Ms.
We must turn off the electricity before going out.
Text 10 Madam, you look nice in this dress.
Thanks, but it's too expensive.
Text 11 Oh, the scene is so beautiful.
Does the boy first meet the horse in the forest?
Text 12 Can anyone tell me when traffic returns to normal?
Who knows? But the waiting time offers us a chance to enjoy the car music.
第二节到此结束。
第三节，听下面四段。
对话或独白。
After B, and to Text 13
每段对话或独白后有几个小题，
从题中所给的
三个选项中选出最佳选项。
听每段对话或独白前，你将有时间阅。
读各个小题，每小题五秒钟。
听完后，各小题将给出五秒钟的作答时间。
每段对话或独白读两遍。
听。
下面一段对话，回答十三至十五三个小题。
Kathy, I'm doing a homework project about family's dreams.
Can I interview you?
Oh, cool. Go ahead.
please face the camera.
1. What do you do?
I'm a student.
I study medicine.
Alright. Question 2.
What is your greatest dream in life?
Well, I hope one day I will be a very good doctor like our parents.
Maybe I will find a solution for cancer.
Great. Any other plans?
Well, I also like fashion.
I hope to be a model in my free time.
What great dreams!
Thanks. 13 I'm doing a homework project about family's dreams.
Can I interview you?
Oh, cool. Go ahead.
Okay, please face the camera.
Question 1. What do you do?
I'm a student.
I study medicine.
Alright. Question 2.
What is your greatest dream in life?
Well, I hope one day I will be a very good doctor like our parents.
Maybe I will find a solution for cancer.
Great. Any other plans?
Well, I also like fashion.
I hope to be a model in my free time.
What great dreams!
Thanks. Question greatest dream life?
听下面一段。
对话，回答十六至十八三个小题
Kathy, I'm a family's Can I interview ahead.
Text 14 I need to exercise and lose some weight.
Can I join you?
I think I need some exercise to be healthy.
Sure. What kind of exercise do you want to do?
I'm not sure.
Swimming or running?
What about going running?
Good. We can run whenever we want.
We can also do other sports like bike riding.
Yes. It's more interesting and relaxing.
A friend of mine goes bike riding every weekend.
We can join his bike riding club and meet other riders.
It must be fun to go bike riding with some new friends.
Great. I'll call my friend tomorrow.
Let's start this weekend.
Okay. I need to exercise and lose some weight.
Can I join you?
I think I need some exercise to be healthy.
Sure. What kind of exercise do you want to do?
I'm not sure.
Swimming or running?
What about going running?
Good. We can run whenever we want.
We can also do other sports like bike riding.
Yes. It's more interesting and relaxing.
A friend of mine goes bike riding every weekend.
We can join his bike riding club and meet other riders.
It must be fun to go bike riding with some new friends.
Great. I'll call my friend tomorrow.
Let's start this weekend.
Okay. Text 15 and I went to Lao She Tea House last night.
听下面一段对话，回答十九至二十二四个小题。
肖飞。
Wow, Sophia. How was it?
It was great.
You know, I wanted to see the Beijing Opera, so she offered to take me there.
We drank tea and watched an opera.
Did you understand the opera?
No, it was difficult to understand the words, but the actors and actresses performed
really well. How long did you stay there?
We arrived there at 7 p.m.
and planned to watch for an hour, but in the end, we stayed there for another hour.
Did you enjoy it?
Well, it was interesting.
I hope to understand more next time.
I want to go there and enjoy it too.
By the way, who Fei told me that
老舍?
老舍.
a great writer.
He is especially famous for his play Tea House.
Xu Fei and I went to Lao She Tea House last night.
Wow, Sophia. How was it?
It was great.
You know, I wanted to see the Beijing Opera, so she offered to take me there.
drank tea and watched an opera.
Did you understand the opera?
No, it was difficult to understand the words, but the actors and actresses performed
really well. How long did you stay there?
We arrived there at 7 p.m.
and planned to watch for an hour, but in the end, we stayed there for another hour.
Did you enjoy it?
Well, it was interesting.
I hope to understand more next time.
I want to go there and enjoy it too.
By the way, who is Lao Xu Fei told me that Lao She is a great writer.
He is especially famous for his play Tea House.
听下面一段读。
白回答二十三至二十五三个小题
He born disabled.
The doctor told his mother he would never speak or be able to do simple things like
tying his shoes or looking after himself.
But when he was three, he drew a map of a place his family visited perfectly.
He knew all the streets after just one visit.
Then when he was four, he amazed doctors and teachers by answering very difficult
math questions correctly.
When he was eight,
he went to classes at a university and taught high -level math at a college.
At the moment, he's writing a book to help teenagers study math.
And he often plays basketball with children at Jacob Center, a charity he started
for disabled children.
Jacob Barnett has an IQ of 170,
which is more than Albert Einstein's.
But he was born disabled.
The doctor told his mother he would never speak or be able to do simple things like
tying his shoes or looking after himself.
But when he was three, he drew a map of a place his family visited perfectly.
He knew all the streets after just one visit.
Then when he was four, he amazed doctors and teachers by answering very difficult
math questions correctly.
When he was eight,
he went to classes at a university and taught high -level math at a college.
At the moment, he's writing a book to help teenagers study math.
And he often plays basketball with children at Jacob Center, a charity he started
for disabled children.
第三节到此结束。
现在你有两分钟的时间，将答案转涂到英语答题卡上。
Thank you for watching!
听力测试到此结束。